## Jelmar Gerritsen

pocket-titan

✓ jelmargerritsen@gmail.com

in jelmargerritsen

pielmar.eu

**3** (+316) 459 479 89

The Hague

Skills

#### **About me**

I'm a driven researcher with a broad academic background. My extensive experience in software engineering allows me to bridge the gap between theoretical research and practical implementation while writing clean and maintainable code. I have expertise in numerical modeling, remote sensing, machine learning and astrodynamics.

#### Education

MSc Aerospace Engineering

**2021 - present** 

Python C++ Rust Julia TypeScript | MATLAB React PyTorch

TU Delft

Track: Planetary Sciences. Course/grade list available upon request. GPA: 7.5/10

BSc Physics & Astronomy

**2016 - 2021** 

Radboud University

Minors: Astronomy, Climate science. Also completed 2 semesters towards a BSc in Computer Science. GPA: 7.0/10

#### **Experience**

Programming teacher

**April** 2021 - May 2021

Stanford University, online

I was a section leader for Standford Code In Place, where I taught Python to an international class of 10 students for around 5 weeks.

Projection technician

**i** January 2020 - June 2021

Stichting LUX

I was responsible for daily cinema operations, scheduling and maintenance.

Teaching assistant

Winter 2019

Radboud University

Course taught: Energy & Sustainability. I designed my own case study on the renewability of a campus building for the students to take on.

Badger keeper

October 2018 - January 2020

Stichting Das & Boom

I volunteered at a shelter for resuce badgers. In addition, I developed a software app using GIS and React for logging & visualising roadkill casualties to aid in conservation efforts.

# **Achievements**

IAC paper selection 📋 2024

My first author paper "NOMAD: Neptune Orbiter Mission for Auroral Detection" was accepted for presentation at the International Astronautical Congress (IAC) in Milan.

BAPC preliminaries 3rd place

**=** 2017

My team and I came in 3rd in the Benelux Algorithm Programming Contest, qualifying us for the finals in Amsterdam.

#### Languages

Dutch		Native
English		C2
German		B2
French		A2
Swedish	000	A1
Chinese	000	A1

### **Projects**

Apygee 🗹 2024

A Python library for creating, manipulating and visualizing Kepler orbits, using popular scientific packages like numpy, scipy and matplotlib. Published on PyPi.

Wikigraph 🔀 **2022** 

A React app for visualizing graph connections between Wikipedia pages. I hand-rolled my own WikiMedia API interface in TypeScript and displayed the graphs using react-three-fiber.